<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome to Dev Pollinate on Dev Pollinate</title><link>https://rex-makusia.github.io/devpollinate/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome to Dev Pollinate on Dev Pollinate</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rex-makusia.github.io/devpollinate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Puppet CD4PE Implementation</title><link>https://rex-makusia.github.io/devpollinate/projects/03-09-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rex-makusia.github.io/devpollinate/projects/03-09-2025/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-overview">🛠 Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Puppet CD4PE (Continuous Delivery for Puppet Enterprise) was implemented to streamline the Puppet code deployment lifecycle. This project integrated &lt;strong>GitLab&lt;/strong> with &lt;strong>Puppet CD4PE&lt;/strong> to enable:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Automated code validation and testing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Environment promotion pipelines.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integration with approval workflows.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="-key-features">⚡ Key Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>GitOps Integration:&lt;/strong> Seamless connection between GitLab and Puppet CD4PE.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Automated Testing:&lt;/strong> Enforced code quality checks using RSpec and Rubocop.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Pipeline Automation:&lt;/strong> Configured multi-stage pipelines for development, testing, and production.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Why I Created Dev Pollinate as a DevOps Engineer with BSP Financial Group Limited</title><link>https://rex-makusia.github.io/devpollinate/blog/why-i-created-dev-pollinate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rex-makusia.github.io/devpollinate/blog/why-i-created-dev-pollinate/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="why-i-created-dev-pollinate-">Why I Created Dev Pollinate ?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>As a DevOps Engineer, I constantly strive to improve my skills, share my experiences, and learn from others in the field. Over the years, I’ve realized the importance of having a platform that allows me to reflect on my journey and contribute to the DevOps community. This is why I created &lt;strong>Dev Pollinate&lt;/strong>—a place to share insights, transformation stories, and ideas that can inspire and help others in their DevOps endeavors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Postilion Host Rebuild Automation</title><link>https://rex-makusia.github.io/devpollinate/projects/02-20-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rex-makusia.github.io/devpollinate/projects/02-20-2024/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-overview">🛠 Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Postilion Host Rebuild Automation&lt;/strong> project was developed to streamline the rebuilding and cleaning of Postilion hosts in a financial transaction environment. Previously, the team had to manually clean up test environments, which was a time-consuming process that took &lt;strong>weeks&lt;/strong> to complete. This project leverages &lt;strong>GitLab&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Pipelines&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Runners&lt;/strong> to automate critical tasks such as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Registry Host Level Cleanup&lt;/strong>: Automatically cleaning up registry entries from previous configurations to ensure a clean environment for the next deployment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Microsoft SQL Server Cleanup&lt;/strong>: Automated cleanup of SQL Server instances, removing old configurations and ensuring the database environment is ready for new deployments.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="-key-features">⚡ Key Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>GitLab Integration&lt;/strong>: GitLab CI/CD pipelines and runners manage the automation tasks, providing seamless integration and version control.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Registry Host Cleanup&lt;/strong>: Uses custom scripts in the pipeline to identify and remove outdated registry entries, ensuring hosts are clean for new configurations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SQL Server Cleanup&lt;/strong>: Automates the cleanup of Microsoft SQL Server, removing obsolete data and resetting configurations to improve performance and security.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Automation of Rebuilds&lt;/strong>: Fully automated host rebuild process using pipelines for environment consistency and scalability.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Test Environment Optimization&lt;/strong>: Reduces the time spent cleaning test environments from weeks to &lt;strong>hours&lt;/strong>, improving overall efficiency and throughput.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="-benefits">🚀 Benefits&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Efficiency&lt;/strong>: Significantly reduced manual intervention by automating the host rebuild and cleanup processes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Consistency&lt;/strong>: Ensured consistent host environments by automating cleanup tasks, eliminating human error.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Scalability&lt;/strong>: Streamlined the process for scaling the deployment of hosts, allowing the environment to grow efficiently without compromising quality.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Time Savings&lt;/strong>: What previously took weeks to clean up in the test environment is now accomplished in &lt;strong>hours&lt;/strong>, accelerating development and testing cycles.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="-goals-achieved">🎯 Goals Achieved&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Successfully automated the &lt;strong>host rebuild process&lt;/strong> for Postilion environments.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrated &lt;strong>GitLab Pipelines&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Runners&lt;/strong> to handle complex tasks like &lt;strong>registry cleanup&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>SQL Server reset&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduced test environment cleanup time from weeks to &lt;strong>hours&lt;/strong>, enabling faster iterations and deployments.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improved overall testing efficiency and reduced downtime for development teams.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr></description></item></channel></rss>